Hello, welcome to Radio Money Nine.
I'm Divya, and you're listening to
our daily podcast.
Lenovo, a Chinese company that manufactures computers, laptops, and other IT hardware, is facing an Income Tax
Department investigation.
Reports indicate that on Wednesday, Income Tax
Department officials searched Lenovo's
offices in Puducherry and Bengaluru. The
report also states that, in
addition to the raid, Income Tax Department officials
also questioned senior Lenovo officials. The
Vedanta Group is preparing to demerge its businesses, ranging from aluminum and steel to
oil, and
list several companies. The
Anil Agarwal-led
group is grappling with tax payments.
According to a report, the group has informed its
lenders about the restructuring plan.
Abu Dhabi Investment Authority, the world's leading sovereign wealth fund, may
invest another $600 million in Reliance Industries.
Google and Facebook may have to pay.
Companies like Google, Facebook, and Twitter will
no longer receive the tax relief they currently receive from the government, and they may now be required to pay
18% tax.  It has been
said that the tax
payable to all these companies under IGST has now been
waived and
in this regard the government has also issued a notice. The
Income Tax Department has sent a notice to the general insurance company ICC Lombard for tax arrears of Rs 1728.9 crore. This arrears are for a
period of 5 years. Apart from this,
notices have also been issued to 6 other insurance companies. In
this way, the combined tax liability of all the companies is
said to be around Rs 3000 crore. The
Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) has rejected the
SEBI's order of Rs 65 lakh on Apollo Tyres. The
fine was imposed in the year 2003 in the case of buyback of shares. The
main companies have taken Rs 2.5 crore from Adani.
After this news came,
Atani Power's share
fluctuated on Thursday and it
closed at 375 with a slight decline. The
problems of China's largest real estate company Agar Grand do not
seem to be getting resolved. The
sword of liquidation is hanging over the company and meanwhile the chairman of the company has been
kept under police surveillance.
After this, the trading of the company's share on Thursday  The
founder of the country's leading paint company Asia Paints, Ashwin Dani, passed away on Thursday.
79-year-old Dani was the non-
executive chairman of the company. On Thursday, Asia
Paints' shares were sold at Rs 30,169.
Barbeque Nation Hospitality Limited and Red
Apple Kitchen Consultancy have jointly
decided to acquire 53.3% stake in Blue Planet Food Pvt.
This deal is worth around Rs 23.5 crore. The
market
regulator has imposed a fine of Rs 500,000
on irregularities in customer claim settlement. The company has
already owned 50% of the company. After this news, the
company's shares strengthened on Thursday
but were eventually sold.
Troubled attack company Byju's said that
it will not conduct campus placements this year. The
company has taken this decision as part of a massive cost-cutting measure. The
company has so far laid off
more than 13,000 people due to corruption.
Quick service coffee and food brand Third Wave
Coffee has invested Rs 3.5 crore in Series A funding round.
Best Bridge Capital of Kriya
and Install Investors participated in this round in the form of Nahin Bhejoo Ko. The
listing of its shares under Yatra Online's IPO was not good. The company's shares were
subscribed at a discount of about 10% on Thursday from Rs 127 on SEBI and Rs 130 on BSE. Its issue price was Rs 142
and on the second day of investment, it was
subscribed twice with Mahesh Das Sune Decimal. Its
retail subscription was about 1.5 times. The
company wants to raise about Rs 152 crore through the issue of CPO. The
shares of the government company Oil India reached a
52-week
high of Rs 305 on Thursday. Due to the
increase in oil and gas production and
better earning opportunities,
better prospects of growth are visible for the company.
At the end of the trading, the shares slipped five
percent and closed strongly at 292.45 paise. The
shares of Oil India
saw a gain of about 11% on Thursday and
reached the level of Rs 2160.  It has estimated to achieve a revenue of Rs 1000 crore by the financial year 2018.
At the end of the trading, the
shares of its parent company C Info System
closed at Rs 203880 with a rise of around 7:30. That's all for now.
In today's Company Salt Podcast,
Dinesh Agra had prepared the journey of the airport. For more news of the corporate world, keep
listening to Radio 99 and download
our Money Nine.